A Guide to the Records of the Ashton Heights Civic Association, 1915-1995
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Records of the Ashton Heights Civic Association, 1915-1995
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 79
4 boxes.
Ashton Heights Civic Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Donated in 1998 by Jim Terpstra, historian of the Association.
Historical Information
The Ashton Heights Civic Association is open to all residents, 18 or older, who are residents or real property owners in Ashton Heights, a residential neighborhood in Arlington, Virginia. The boundaries are Wilson Boulevard and Tenth Street to the north, Irving Street to the east, Arlington Boulevard to the south, and Glebe road to the west.
Scope and Content
Record Group 79 houses the records of the Ashton Heights Civic Association. The collection measures approximately 1.5 linear feet, and dates from 1915 to 1998, with the bulk of the material dating from the mid-1970s to 1998. Types of materials include bylaws, minutes, newsletters, correspondence, financial records, history files, printed reports, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia.
Minutes, newsletters, and reports reflect neighborhood concerns over the years. Topics include zoning issues such as the Clarendon and Virginia Square sector plans; traffic patterns; the proposed extension of North Quincy Street; the historic designation for the Buckingham Apartments; the Ashton Heights Neighborhood Conservation Plan; and neighborhood activities such as gardening and social events. There are photographs and ephemera in Series 9, Clippings, Photographs, Memorabilia, including eight small cards advertising dances held at the Ashton Heights Women's Club building.
Arrangement
RG 79 is divided into eight series by type of material: bylaws, minutes, financial records, correspondence, newsletters, local history, printed reports and studies, and clippings, photographs, and memorabilia. Arrangement within Series 1-5 and Series 8 is generally chronological; within Series 6 and Series 7 generally alphabetical by folder title. Folder titles in quotes [""] retain the original title written on the folder by civic association members. Folders containing photographs have an asterisk [*] after the file name.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Researchers interested in Arlington neighborhood civic associations should consult RG 14, Records of the Arlington County Civic Federation, and RG 15, Records of Neighborhood Civic Associations. Those interested in the Ashton Heights neighborhood should consult PG 205, Ashton Heights Photographs, a collection of black and white photographic prints of houses in the neighborhood, RG 112, Ashton Heights Neighborhood Survey, and RG 151, Ashton Heights Women's Club Records.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Ashton Heights (Arlington, Va.); Neighborhoods.; Community organization.; Citizens' associations; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Bylaws and Procedures
  - Bylaws, Rules of Order, Procedures, 1981, 1991 (Box 1)
  - "SOP," 1993, n.d. (Box 1)
- Minutes and Agendas
  - Executive Committee Agendas and Minutes, October 1990-July 1991 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Agendas and Minutes, July 1991-July 1992 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Agendas and Minutes, August 1992-May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Agendas and Minutes, June 1993-April 1994 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Agendas and Minutes, 1998 (Box 1)
  - General Meeting Agendas and Minutes, September 1990-May 1991 (Box 1)
  - General Meeting Agendas and Minutes, September 1991-May 1992 (Box 1)
  - General Meeting Agendas and Minutes, September 1992-April 1993 (Box 1)
  - General Meeting Agendas and Minutes, September 1993-May 1994 (Box 1)
  - Handrwritten Meeting Minutes, 1990, n.d. (Box 1)
- Financial Reports
  - Financial Reports September 1990-August 1993 (1) (Box 1)
  - Financial Reports, September 1990-August 1993 (2) (Box 1)
  - "Budgets," 1984, 1990-1993, 1998, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Meeting Notes and Correspondence, 1986, 1989, August 1990-June 1991 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Notes and Correspondence, September 1991-September 1993 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and Information about Traffic Circles, 1993 (Box 1)
- Newsletters
  - Ashton Heights Perspective, 1973, May 1974-May 1975 (Box 1)
  - Ashton Heights Eagle, September 1975-May 1977 (Box 1)
  - Ashton Heights Eagle, October 1977-January 1979 (Box 1)
  - Ashton Heights February 1979-May 1979 (Box 1)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1979-May 1981 (Box 1)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1981-May 1983 (Box 1)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1983-May 1985 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1985-May 1987 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1987-May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1988-May 1989 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1989-May 1990 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1990-May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1991-May 1992 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1992-June 1993 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights Civic Association Newsletter, September 1993-May 1994 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights News, January, March, September, October 1995, January 1996 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights News, February 1997-May 1998 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights News, October 1998-May 1999 (Box 2)
  - Ashton Heights News, September 1999-May 2000 (Box 3)
  - Ashton Heights News, September 2000-January 2001 (Box 3)
  - Ashton Heights News, January, September-November 2003, January-May 2004 (Box 3)
  - Ashton Heights News, September 2004-May 2005 (Box 3)
- Membership
  - "Committees," 1993, n.d. (Box 3)
  - "Member Lists," 1993, 1995 (Box 3)
- Local History
  - Ashton Heights Local History Documents (Box 3)
  - "Buckingham: Housing Laboratory," 1938 (Box 3)
  - Buckingham Historic District Information, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - "Historic Resources in the Clarendon Commercial District," 1985 (Box 3)
  - Local Historical Articles, 1924, 1980, 1982 (Box 3)
  - "Parkway's Past," 1964 (Box 3)
- Reports and Studies
  - Arlington County News Releases, November 1990-May 1991 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Sector Plans, 1985, 1989-1991, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Neighborhood Conservation Program Plans for Ashton Heights, 1976, 1991, 1994, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Neighborhood Conservation Survey for Ashton Heights, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Property Listings for Ashton Heights (Box 3)
  - Quincy Street Extension Studies, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Quincy Street Extension Studies, 1992-1994 (Box 4)
  - Arlington County Publications, 1990-1995, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Zoning Issues, 1986, 1995, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Community Environmental Health Assessment, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Planning Information for County Citizens, ca. 1997 (Box 4)
- Clippings, Photographs, Memorabilia
  - Clippings about Ashton Heights and Arlington, 1976-1998 (Box 4)
  - Ashton Heights Photographs and Memorabilia, 1915, 1933-1952 * (Box 4)
  - Photographs and Negatives, ca. 1995 * (Box 4)
  - "Press Coverage," 1997, 1998, n.d. (Box 4)
- Community Issues
  - Traffic Circle at 5th and Jackson Streets, 1991-1993, n.d. (Box 4)
  - "N. Lincoln (Persh. to 5th) Coach Lights," n.d. (Box 4)
  - Arlington Arts Center, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - "Development," 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1993-1995, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Ashton Heights Food Co-Op, n.d. (Box 4)